<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gac on Matt Andreko</title>
    <link>https://www.mattandreko.com/categories/gac/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Gac on Matt Andreko</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <atom:link href="https://www.mattandreko.com/categories/gac/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding DLL files in the GAC</title>
      <link>https://www.mattandreko.com/2011/10/14/finding-dll-files-in-the-gac/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2011 07:20:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mattandreko.com/2011/10/14/finding-dll-files-in-the-gac/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So last night I was working on a project where I needed a specific version of a .net assembly that was installed somewhere on my system, but I could not locate it by a common search. Whenever I would open up C:\Windows\Assembly\ I could see the file and the multiple versions that I had installed. However, from that window, you can not copy the files out. All I wanted, was to copy the file to my local source branch, and include it in source control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stumbled upon an &lt;a href=&#34;http://stackoverflow.com/questions/714907/how-to-extract-an-assembly-from-the-gac/714919#714919&#34;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; that mentioned being able to go to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;C:\Windows\Assembly\GAC_msil&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This worked out perfectly. I found the assembly, sorted through the version numbers, and copied the dll files that I needed. My app now works marvelously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m guessing that I could also achieve the same results, loading the assembly from the GAC using some sort of assembly binding, but I honestly haven&amp;rsquo;t looked enough into it to figure it out, and I needed these dll files in my source control in case another machine I download it to didn&amp;rsquo;t have the libraries installed, so this method worked fine for me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>