<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rails on Matt Andreko</title>
    <link>http://test.andreko.net/categories/rails/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rails on Matt Andreko</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2012 17:41:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://test.andreko.net/categories/rails/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>PWB Conclusions and the Future</title>
      <link>http://test.andreko.net/2012/06/24/pwb-conclusions-and-the-future/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jun 2012 17:41:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://test.andreko.net/2012/06/24/pwb-conclusions-and-the-future/</guid>
      <description>The results As I posted previously, I was taking the PWB course from Offensive Security. I am happy to report that I passed with flying colors (100%)! This is the best email I&amp;rsquo;ve ever received:
 Advice for new students During the course, I learned several things, including many things about myself. * Do the PDF/Video work first. If you wait until the end, you will hate your life. It&amp;rsquo;s so droll and boring.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing Guard gem causes tests to fail - Solved</title>
      <link>http://test.andreko.net/2011/08/18/installing-guard-gem-causes-tests-to-fail-solved/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2011 09:14:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://test.andreko.net/2011/08/18/installing-guard-gem-causes-tests-to-fail-solved/</guid>
      <description>I was tinkering with a new rails application, using RSpec2 and Cucumber for my testing. I was able to run all my tests by typing:
rake spec rake cucumber  This worked perfectly, but every time I&amp;rsquo;d make a change, I&amp;rsquo;d have to run both commands. So I looked into the Guard gem, after watching the excellent RailsCast by Ryan Bates.
I started by adding to my gemfile:
gem &#39;guard-spork&#39; gem &#39;guard-rspec&#39; gem &#39;guard-cucumber&#39;  Then to configure guard, I ran:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cucumber testing woes - spaces</title>
      <link>http://test.andreko.net/2011/08/16/cucumber-testing-woes-spaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Aug 2011 22:47:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://test.andreko.net/2011/08/16/cucumber-testing-woes-spaces/</guid>
      <description>So I&amp;rsquo;m working along, writing my tests, and I run into an issue where my Cucumber test is failing. I go to check it out, and see why. This is what I see:
 I&amp;rsquo;ve slightly outlined the relevant data in yellow. I went back, and copy/pasted the data from the creation from my factories, to the expectation of text. It still gave the same error. I was dumbfounded, as I can clearly see the exact same text in my &amp;ldquo;And I should see&amp;rdquo; as well as the actual results.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>