<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Browsers on Matt Andreko</title>
    <link>https://www.mattandreko.com/categories/browsers/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Browsers on Matt Andreko</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <atom:link href="https://www.mattandreko.com/categories/browsers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Poor UI Experience</title>
      <link>https://www.mattandreko.com/blog/2011-08-17-poor-ui-experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2011 08:23:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mattandreko.com/blog/2011-08-17-poor-ui-experience/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was recently signing up for &lt;a href=&#34;http://about.me&#34;&gt;about.me&lt;/a&gt; because it sounded like a neat little simple blurb about yourself. When trying to sign up, after entering my email address, and password, I was brought to a page asking for some basic info. However, I couldn&amp;rsquo;t figure out how to submit it. I was given this error:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;img-responsive&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;https://www.mattandreko.com/img/about.me_validation_error.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I filled out all the required data, and left the optional parts empty. However, it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t submit. So then, I tried entering a short bit of information in the optional parts, and still got the same error. I tried multiple times, I even shut down my browser and went back to the site. Eventually, I switched from Chrome to Internet Explorer, and it let me continue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now when you look at this experience, you see that it&amp;rsquo;s fairly trivial. However, the audience that they are targeting, may not be the mostsavvy when it comes to computers. Half the non-technical people I talk to, don&amp;rsquo;t even know what their browser is, and surely wouldn&amp;rsquo;t know that this error was an issue with one browser over another.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I run into this issue quite often in development, and I know that I have to test it in all major browsers. All browsers need to work, or I won&amp;rsquo;t succeed. Had I not switched browsers, I would have not been able to finish signing up for an account. While this is just a social site, what if it were a bank, or something important? You absolutely have to test for this sort of thing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>