<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Rant on Matt Andreko</title>
    <link>http://test.andreko.net/categories/rant/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Rant on Matt Andreko</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <atom:link href="http://test.andreko.net/categories/rant/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Multiple Hover.com Security Issues</title>
      <link>http://test.andreko.net/2013/02/28/multiple-hover.com-security-issues/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 12:05:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://test.andreko.net/2013/02/28/multiple-hover.com-security-issues/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m a customer of &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hover.com&#34;&gt;Hover&lt;/a&gt; for my domain name needs. However, that will be changing because I don&amp;rsquo;t believe that they take issues seriously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-first-security-issue&#34;&gt;The first security issue&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was browsing their site, looking for a new domain, and being the constant tinkerer I am, I entered a single quote into the textfield. I noticed an error, and eventually crafted this url:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hover.com/domains/results?q=%27%3E%3Cscript%3Ealert%28%27xss%27%29%3B%3C%2Fscript%3E&#34;&gt;https://www.hover.com/domains/results?q=%27%3E%3Cscript%3Ealert%28%27xss%27%29%3B%3C%2Fscript%3E&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There&amp;rsquo;s nothing magical in that URL, however it demonstrated a real vulnerability in their code:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;img-responsive&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://test.andreko.net/img/hover_original_xss.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;From that point, it could be trivial for an attacker to redirect traffic, and steal user sessions, thus being able to purchase domains with someone else&amp;rsquo;s money.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I reported this issue to them, and had an update within 3 days. They had fixed it, and that URL no longer is vulnerable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-second-security-issue&#34;&gt;The second security issue&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In January, I was discussing Cross-Site Scripting attacks with a coworker, and was talking about the finding I had with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hover.com&#34;&gt;Hover&lt;/a&gt; and how quickly they responded. Upon further investigation, I found that they didn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;i&gt;really&lt;/i&gt; fix it, they just put a band-aid on it. I found the following URL was still vulnerable, but it was a little harder to exploit (onMouseOver):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.hover.com/domains/results?q=hi.com%27%20style%3d%27height:10000px%27%20onmouseover%3d%27alert%28%22xss%22%29&#34;&gt;https://www.hover.com/domains/results?q=hi.com%27%20style%3d%27height:10000px%27%20onmouseover%3d%27alert%28%22xss%22%29&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;img-responsive&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://test.andreko.net/img/hover_second_xss.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This really depressed me, since I have spent my fair share of time being a developer, and I always tried to actually &lt;i&gt;fix&lt;/i&gt;problems, instead of just making the symptom go away. Again, I reported the issue, hoping that I&amp;rsquo;d get another quick turnaround. I asked them to reply within 30 days to indicate their intent on coordinating efforts for remediation. I waited, but I still have no response from them, and it&amp;rsquo;s been over 30 days. I still can&amp;rsquo;t believe they couldn&amp;rsquo;t even respond with a, &amp;ldquo;We&amp;rsquo;re working on it&amp;rdquo;, response.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-billing-issue&#34;&gt;The billing issue&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I received an email from &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hover.com&#34;&gt;Hover&lt;/a&gt; about a domain name of mine expiring soon. I went into my account, and saw that the credit card was expired, so I went to update it. Unfortunately, I got this error instead:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Declined by Fraud Service&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;img-responsive&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://test.andreko.net/img/hover_fraud.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Now, I figured that it was some sort of error, and tried filling it out a couple more times, verifying my card number was correct.After-all, I was only updating the expiration date, nothing else. Unfortunately, all this resulted in were several temporary one dollar charges on my credit card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, I contacted &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hover.com&#34;&gt;Hover&lt;/a&gt; and was disappointed yet again. I stated that I was trying to update my credit card details, and instead they renewed my domain for another year, and said, &amp;ldquo;it failed when you placed the order, but I was able to renew it on my end&amp;rdquo;. I was a bit upset because I hadn&amp;rsquo;t yet decided if I was going to renew through them or not yet, due to the previous security issues. I replied back that it still wasn&amp;rsquo;t helping me for my other domains that will need renewed at some point, and was given these instructions to help troubleshoot:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use only the first and last name, no middle initial.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change the phone number to numbers only, no hyphens.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first one was a bit odd, since most credit card processors want your name &lt;i&gt;exactly&lt;/i&gt;as it shows on the card. I complied, but it did not help. The second issue I thought was absurd because if their system didn&amp;rsquo;t allow hyphens, why didn&amp;rsquo;t they prevent the user from entering them? This is exactly what javascript validation is for. (Note that they should also validate it on the server-side as well)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Their next steps were to have me call, and give them my credit card number over the phone, and have a billing statement ready to verify every bit of information, as if I&amp;rsquo;ve never used a credit card on a website before. It was a bit insulting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-0-day-security-issue&#34;&gt;The 0-day security issue&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had recently read an &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.skullsecurity.org/blog/2010/stuffing-javascript-into-dns-names&#34;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; on inserting javascript into DNS to be used for exploitation. I was tinkering with this idea on my own domain names. Unfortunately, I ended up trying to diagnose why none of the DNS records I created in &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hover.com&#34;&gt;Hover&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/a&gt; DNS Manager ever made it to their public DNS servers. I&amp;rsquo;m guessing they have some filtering on the back-end. Eventually I found that their DNS manager was also vulnerable to Cross-Site Scripting:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;img-responsive&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://test.andreko.net/img/hover_persistent_xss.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;This time, it&amp;rsquo;s a persistent Cross-Site Scripting vulnerability. Every time I navigate to my DNS management screen, I now get a dialog with my cookie. All a user had to do was add a TXT record with the following data:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;lt;img src=&amp;lsquo;&lt;a href=&#34;https://drupal.org/files/images/sup-dog-magnet-c117515921.jpeg&#39;&#34;&gt;https://drupal.org/files/images/sup-dog-magnet-c117515921.jpeg&#39;&lt;/a&gt; onload=&amp;lsquo;javascript:alert(document.cookie)\;&amp;rsquo;&amp;gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They apparently do not even try to filter user-input at all. It&amp;rsquo;s quite depressing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion-tl-dr-http-www-urbandictionary-com-define-php-term-tl-3bdr&#34;&gt;Conclusion (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=tl%3Bdr&#34;&gt;tl;dr&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.hover.com&#34;&gt;Hover&lt;/a&gt; seems to suffer from the inability to filter user-input. This has become a big problem over the last few years. There are many attacks stemming from this seemingly simple attack. I did my best, and tried reporting to them, but they seem unresponsive, and even when they are, it&amp;rsquo;s not always useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will be moving my domains elsewhere. I haven&amp;rsquo;t yet decided where, and I have a bit of time, but I just don&amp;rsquo;t feel safe keeping my data stored somewhere that can&amp;rsquo;t even stop basic &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.owasp.org/index.php/Top_10_2013-T10&#34;&gt;OWASP Top 10&lt;/a&gt; vulnerabilities on their main page.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The demise of &#34;Fast Food&#34;</title>
      <link>http://test.andreko.net/2011/10/16/the-demise-of-fast-food/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2011 10:22:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://test.andreko.net/2011/10/16/the-demise-of-fast-food/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s say you&amp;rsquo;re on your way to church Sunday morning, or just wanting a easy meal after a long day of work. One option for food may be going to a fast food restaurant. This has been the case for my entire life. Lately however I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed a trend. Fast food just isn&amp;rsquo;t fast anymore. Whenever the wife and I go see her family in Lafayette, we will stop somewhere to get breakfast as a treat. No matter where we stop, we sit in the drive-thru line for 20 minutes. Since when is 20 minutes considered fast?  For example this morning we stopped by McDonalds. There were 6 or so cars ahead of us at the Lebanon location off of 65. We put in our order at 9:28. We then watched as it was taking 7 minutes per car at first. The car in front of us waited for only 2 cups of coffee. We eventually got our food at 9:47. The guy handing out the food was very personable, as he handed us the bag saying &amp;ldquo;Here&amp;rdquo;, in a grumpy tone, shutting the window with a slam. As we are driving on our way we find that we didn&amp;rsquo;t even get the sandwiches done correctly. We had 3 bagel sandwiches and one just randomly had no cheese but tasted like it had cinnamon and sugar on it instead. This isnt an isolated event. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter what time or day, I see the kids making food with no sense of urgency. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;m turning into a grumpy old man very early on in life, but I can&amp;rsquo;t seem to validate fast food as a 20 minute wait. For some, that&amp;rsquo;s their lunch break at work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sprint iPhone 4S pre-order fiasco</title>
      <link>http://test.andreko.net/2011/10/07/sprint-iphone-4s-pre-order-fiasco/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2011 08:09:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://test.andreko.net/2011/10/07/sprint-iphone-4s-pre-order-fiasco/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So like many people, I wanted the new iPhone 4S.  Since the wife unit is on Sprint, and I&amp;rsquo;m on AT&amp;amp;T, we started looking at plans.  Sprint offers a nicer family plan and lets her upgrade to a smartphone, while letting me have the iPhone.  So we decided to make the switch, and do the pre-order.  I called last night to verify the ordering process, and make sure that I could still get the $200 price while not using her upgrade credit.  I was told that the phone would become available at 12:01 AM PST.  I woke up at 5 AM (No way am I waking up at 3 AM) to put in the pre-order.  I tried clicking the massive preorder button:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;img-responsive&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://test.andreko.net/img/sprint_1.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;!-- more --&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I did this though, it was trying to replace my wife&amp;rsquo;s phone with the iPhone. This was not cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I log out, close my browser and try again. This time I go to &amp;ldquo;My Account&amp;rdquo;, and select &amp;ldquo;Add a new phone to share minutes&amp;rdquo;. When I did this, I could add a new phone, but we couldn&amp;rsquo;t seem to get it with the family plan setup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I log out, close my browser and try again. This time I go to &amp;ldquo;Shop&amp;rdquo;, and select &amp;ldquo;Plans&amp;rdquo;. I select the family plan that we want. It instructs me to add a phone, so I select the iPhone 4S. It then tells me that I need to add a second plan. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t let me use her existing phone anywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decide that maybe I&amp;rsquo;ll stop trying to be such a technology zealot and try using an actual phone. I call them up, and their callcenters aren&amp;rsquo;t open. Apparently they don&amp;rsquo;t open until 6 AM CST. I wait until then in my car, and then call them. After finding out that my wife didn&amp;rsquo;t know her correct security pin or security answer, I had them send it to her email. I checked her email from my phone (something I won&amp;rsquo;t be able to do with the Sprint iPhone unfortunately), and found the answers. The security pin was way off, but the security answer was pretty much what I told the Sprint representative. I just gave an unabbreviated version. Unfortunately they don&amp;rsquo;t get to see the security answer to compare to, they type in what you tell them, and the computer compares it. So if it&amp;rsquo;s off by just a little bit, it&amp;rsquo;s not letting you in. Awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I give the representative the pin, and he lets me access her account. I tell him about wanting to pre-order the iPhone 4S, and my problems with the website. He asks me to try again, which unfortunately I can&amp;rsquo;t do, since I&amp;rsquo;m in my car. He puts me on hold for a few minutes, and tells me that there&amp;rsquo;s some sort of problem, that they can&amp;rsquo;t order the iPhone 4S yet, and maybe I should &amp;ldquo;try back in a few hours&amp;rdquo;. I explain that I&amp;rsquo;ll be at work, and not able to just spend all day calling until their ordering system decides to work. He says, &amp;ldquo;Well, maybe too many people are ordering right now, so I can&amp;rsquo;t order. Try it online again.&amp;rdquo; He tells me because of my issues with the website, to just order the phone under my wife&amp;rsquo;s account, but under an individual plan. I ask about number porting, and he said that Sprint could assign it a number, and then when it&amp;rsquo;s delivered, and I open the box, they can port my AT&amp;amp;T number over. They could then fix the plan to be a family plan. I asked, and he confirmed that there would be no cost penalty for this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I go to work, and quickly start to pre-order the phone, as to not waste a bunch of work time. I get to ordering under the individual plan, and they ask about porting the number. The representative said they wouldn&amp;rsquo;t need it, but I figured since they ask, I&amp;rsquo;ll enter it, and have it ready. Awesome for me! Then I see this:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;img-responsive&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://test.andreko.net/img/sprint_security.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve highlighted the parts that worry me. Firstly, notice that for some reason now, my browser is warning me that there&amp;rsquo;s an issue with the security. I&amp;rsquo;m smart enough to figure out what it is luckily, since I work in the IT field. The encryption is working, they just have an HTTPS page that has images on it referencing HTTP. This is considered a no-no in web programming. Then the more alarming issue: They want my account number, password, and SSN for AT&amp;amp;T. I could see using my account number as a reference for talking with AT&amp;amp;T, no problem. However why do they need my password? We have always taught users to NEVER give out your password to anyone, especially on a page that the HTTPS isn&amp;rsquo;t working properly. Since the representative said they could assign it the new number and port on delivery, I opted for the option to assign me a new number instead of filling out this form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually I get to this point:&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;figure class=&#34;img-responsive&#34;&gt;
    
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://test.andreko.net/img/sprint_complete.png&#34; /&gt;
    
    
&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s hope that Sprint can actually deliver on their promise of fixing everything. Everyone likes to complain about AT&amp;amp;T being incompetent, but so far, I&amp;rsquo;m not really having that much confidence in Sprint either. We&amp;rsquo;ll just have to see what happens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the security issues on their page, Sprint should know better. Or at least the techs they paid to do the work should know better. There&amp;rsquo;s no reason that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t have been caught in testing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>