<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Getoffmylawn on Matt Andreko</title>
    <link>https://www.mattandreko.com/categories/getoffmylawn/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Getoffmylawn on Matt Andreko</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <atom:link href="https://www.mattandreko.com/categories/getoffmylawn/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>The demise of &#34;Fast Food&#34;</title>
      <link>https://www.mattandreko.com/blog/2011-10-16-demise-of-fast-food/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2011 10:22:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.mattandreko.com/blog/2011-10-16-demise-of-fast-food/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s say you&amp;rsquo;re on your way to church Sunday morning, or just wanting a easy meal after a long day of work. One option for food may be going to a fast food restaurant. This has been the case for my entire life. Lately however I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed a trend. Fast food just isn&amp;rsquo;t fast anymore. Whenever the wife and I go see her family in Lafayette, we will stop somewhere to get breakfast as a treat. No matter where we stop, we sit in the drive-thru line for 20 minutes. Since when is 20 minutes considered fast?  For example this morning we stopped by McDonalds. There were 6 or so cars ahead of us at the Lebanon location off of 65. We put in our order at 9:28. We then watched as it was taking 7 minutes per car at first. The car in front of us waited for only 2 cups of coffee. We eventually got our food at 9:47. The guy handing out the food was very personable, as he handed us the bag saying &amp;ldquo;Here&amp;rdquo;, in a grumpy tone, shutting the window with a slam. As we are driving on our way we find that we didn&amp;rsquo;t even get the sandwiches done correctly. We had 3 bagel sandwiches and one just randomly had no cheese but tasted like it had cinnamon and sugar on it instead. This isnt an isolated event. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t matter what time or day, I see the kids making food with no sense of urgency. Maybe I&amp;rsquo;m turning into a grumpy old man very early on in life, but I can&amp;rsquo;t seem to validate fast food as a 20 minute wait. For some, that&amp;rsquo;s their lunch break at work.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>